<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "csdgm2.dtd">
<?xml-stylesheet href="FGDC_V2.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
<pubdate>2004</pubdate>
<title>USGS High Resolution Orthoimage USNG 17SNV685945, Greensboro-Winston Salem, NC</title>
<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Sioux Falls, SD</pubplace>
<publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
</pubinfo>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>This data set consists of 0.3-meter pixel resolution (approximately 1-foot), natural color orthoimages covering the urban area footprint.  An orthoimage is remotely sensed image data in which displacement of features in the image caused by terrain relief and sensor orientation have been mathematically removed. Orthoimagery combines the image characteristics of a photograph with the geometric qualities of a map.  The design accuracy is estimated not to exceed 3-meter diagonal RMSE (2.12m RMSE in X or Y). Each orthoimage provides imagery over a 1500- by 1500-meter block on the ground. There is no image overlap between adjacent files. The projected coordinate system is UTM with a NAD83 datum. The naming convention is based on the U.S. National Grid (USNG), taking the coordinates of the SW corner of the orthoimage.</abstract>
<purpose>This data depicts geographic features on the surface of the earth.  It was created to provide easily accessible geospatial data which is readily available to enhance the capability of Federal, State, and local emergency responders, as well as plan for homeland security efforts.  This data also supports The National Map.</purpose>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>20020404</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<current>ground condition</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>irregular</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-80.23895146677656</westbc>
<eastbc>-80.2222875374658</eastbc>
<northbc>36.1062379862651</northbc>
<southbc>36.09271549105445</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>None</themekt>
<themekey>0.3 meter orthoimage</themekey>
<themekey>rectified photograph</themekey>
<themekey>rectified image</themekey>
<themekey>orthophoto</themekey>
<themekey>natural color orthophoto</themekey>
<themekey>orthoimage</themekey>
<themekey>image map</themekey>
</theme>
<place>
<placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce, 1995, Countries, dependencies, areas of special sovereignty, and their principal administrative divisions, Federal Information Processing Standard (FIPS) 10-4): Washington, D.C., National Institute of Standards and Technology.</placekt>
<placekey>US</placekey>
</place>
<place>
<placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce, 1987, Codes for the Identification of the States, the District of Columbia and the outlying areas of the United States, and associated areas (Federal Information Processing Standard (FIPS) 5-2): Washington, D.C., National Institute of Standards and Technology.</placekt>
<placekey>NC</placekey>
</place>
<place>
<placekt>None</placekt>
<placekey>Greensboro-Winston Salem, NC</placekey>
</place>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>None.  However, users should be aware that temporal changes may have occurred since this data set was collected and that some parts of this data may no longer represent actual surface conditions.  Users should not use this data for critical applications without a full awareness of it's limitations.  Acknowledgment of the U.S. Geological Survey would be appreciated for products derived from these data.</useconst>
<datacred>The Lidar data used in the orthorectification process for this imagery was developed for the Floodplain       Mapping Program, North Carolina Division of Emergency Management.</datacred>
<native>Z/I Imaging Orthopro 4.0, Windows 2000 SP2</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<attracc>
<attraccr>During photographic reproduction of the source photographs, limited analog dodging (radiometric editing) is performed to improve image quality. Analog dodging consists of holding back light from certain areas of the sensitized photographic material to avoid overexposure. The diapositive is inspected to ensure clarity and radiometric uniformity. Diapositive image brightness values are collected with a minimum of image quality manipulation. Image brightness values may deviate from the brightness values of the original images because of image value interpolation during the scanning and rectification processes. Radiometry is verified by visual inspection of the digital orthophoto with the original unrectified image to determine if the digital orthophoto has the same or better image quality as the original unrectified input image. Slight systematic radiometric differences can be detected between adjacent orthoimage files; these are due primarily to differences in source photograph capture dates and sun angles along flight lines when the aerial photographs were taken. These differences can be observed in an image's general lightness or darkness when it is compared to adjacent orthoimage file coverages. Tonal balancing may be performed over a group of images during the mosaicking process which may serve to lighten or darken adjacent images for better color tone matching.</attraccr>
</attracc>
<logic>All GeoTIFF tagged data and image file sizes are validated using commercial GIS software to ensure proper loading before being archived.   This validation procedure ensures correct physical format and field values for tagged elements.  Seamlines and tile edges are visually inspected.  Seamline mismatches are not corrected unless the overall displacement exceeds one meter.</logic>
<complete>Orthoimages are visually inspected for completeness to ensure that no gaps or image misplacements exist within and between adjacent images. These images are derived by mosaicking multiple images to ensure complete coverage. Source imagery is cloud free. Photography was flown during leaf-off in deciduous vegetation regions. Coastal areas and international boundary regions may have areas without images (void areas) in parts of the coverage. These void areas have a radiometric value of either zero (black) or 128 (uniform gray).</complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>The horizontal positional accuracy and the assurance of that accuracy depend, in part, on the accuracy of the data inputs to the rectification process.  The location of existing USGS photoidentifiable ground control were evaluated on the Geotiff image and compared with their ground values in order to determine an overall accuracy for the project.   After image coordinate measurement was completed  an RMSE for the diagonal error was calculated for the orthoimages within the project.  This value is an estimate of the horizontal accuracy of the tile expressed in meters.</horizpar>
<qhorizpa>
<horizpav>.7</horizpav>
<horizpae>Federal Geographic Data Committee, 1998, Geospatial Positioning Accuracy Standard, Part 3, National Standard for Spatial Data Accuracy, FGDC-STD-007.3-1998</horizpae>
</qhorizpa>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Sanborn of Colorado, LLC</origin>
<pubdate>Unpublished material</pubdate>
<title>Airborne GPS Control</title>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<typesrc>various media</typesrc>
<srctime>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>20020404</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
</srctime>
<srccitea>Control_input</srccitea>
<srccontr>Control consists of both Airborne GPS to provide camera station positions and photoidentifiable surveyed ground control for ground reference.</srccontr>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Sanborn of Colorado, LLC</origin>
<pubdate>unknown</pubdate>
<title>GSO 4 029</title>
<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<srcscale>15000</srcscale>
<typesrc>stable-base material.</typesrc>
<srctime>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>20020404</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
</srctime>
<srccitea>PHOTO1</srccitea>
<srccontr>True color stable-base aerial photography film flown at 7,500 feet above average ground elevation. Provides the imagery for the digital orthoimage.</srccontr>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Sanborn of Colorado, LLC</origin>
<pubdate>unknown</pubdate>
<title>GSO 4 181</title>
<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<srcscale>15000</srcscale>
<typesrc>stable-base material</typesrc>
<srctime>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>20020404</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
</srctime>
<srccitea>PHOTO2</srccitea>
<srccontr>True color stable-base aerial photography film flown at 7,500 feet above average ground elevation. Provides the imagery for the digital orthoimage.</srccontr>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Sanborn of Colorado, LLC</origin>
<pubdate>unknown</pubdate>
<title>GSO 4 028</title>
<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<srcscale>15000</srcscale>
<typesrc>stable-base material</typesrc>
<srctime>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>20020404</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
</srctime>
<srccitea>PHOTO3</srccitea>
<srccontr>True color stable-base aerial photography film flown at 7,500 feet above average ground elevation. Provides the imagery for the digital orthoimage.</srccontr>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Sanborn of Colorado, LLC</origin>
<pubdate>unknown</pubdate>
<title>GSO 4 180</title>
<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<srcscale>15000</srcscale>
<typesrc>stable-base material</typesrc>
<srctime>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>20020404</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
</srctime>
<srccitea>PHOTO4</srccitea>
<srccontr>True color stable-base aerial photography film flown at 7,500 feet above average ground elevation. Provides the imagery for the digital orthoimage.</srccontr>
</srcinfo>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Floodplain Mapping Program, North Carolina Division of Emergency Management.</origin>
<pubdate>unknown</pubdate>
<title>Floodplain Mapping Program LIDAR data</title>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<typesrc>digital file</typesrc>
<srctime>
<timeinfo>
<rngdates>
<begdate>200101</begdate>
<enddate>200303</enddate>
</rngdates>
</timeinfo>
<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
</srctime>
<srccitea>DEM</srccitea>
<srccontr>The LIDAR elevation provided by North Carolina Floodplain Mapping Program was formatted as 20-foot gridded DEMs or as bare earth mass points.  Used to provide ground elevations for orthorectification process.</srccontr>
</srcinfo>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Each image was scanned from film-stable source at a resolution of 20 micrometers.  Airborne GPS provided the camera station X, Y, and Z coordinates and was used to control a conventional aerotriangulation block solution.  Available USGS photoidentifiable ground control was used to test the results of the aerotriangulation adjustment.  External orientation parameters derived from the aerotriangulation solution were used to provide the horizontal control for each photograph.  Vertical control for the orthorectification process was obtained from various sources including photogrammetric autocorrelation and Floodplain Mapping Program, North Carolina Division of Emergency Management LIDAR data.  During the orthorectification process, elevation data were extracted and resampled to meet user-specified intervals and bounds.

The orthorectified imagery is resampled to a 0.3 meter ground resolution with a ground extent of 1500-meters by 1500-meters.  Each 1500- by 1500-meter orthoimage is generated from a mosaic created from multiple photographs.  Tonal balancing is automatically performed over each work block of contiguous images during the mosaicking process.  A single tonal balancing operation was performed over the project area in its entirety.  Orthorectification and mosaicking were performed using Z/I Imaging OrthoPro 4.00.00.05 running on Windows 2000 SP2.  Resampling to 0.3 meter was done using exponential.  Individual orthoimages are bounded by UTM grid lines which are evenly divisible by 1500.  Final output is as an uncompressed GeoTiff file.

All orthoimages are individually inspected for content, misalignments along mosaic seamlines, and void areas.  Source information was collected and verified manually during the production process.</procdesc>
<procdate>20040801</procdate>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>raster</direct>
<rastinfo>
<rasttype>pixel</rasttype>
<rowcount>5000</rowcount>
<colcount>5000</colcount>
</rastinfo>
</spdoinfo>
<spref>
<horizsys>
<planar>
<gridsys>
<gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>
<utm>
<utmzone>17</utmzone>
<transmer>
<sfctrmer>0.9996</sfctrmer>
<longcm>-81.0000</longcm>
<latprjo>0.0</latprjo>
<feast>500000</feast>
<fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
</transmer>
</utm>
</gridsys>
<planci>
<plance>row and column</plance>
<coordrep>
<absres>0.3</absres>
<ordres>0.3</ordres>
</coordrep>
<plandu>meters</plandu>
</planci>
</planar>
<geodetic>
<horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
<ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
<semiaxis>6378137</semiaxis>
<denflat>298.2572221</denflat>
</geodetic>
</horizsys>
</spref>
<eainfo>
<overview>
<eaover>For natural color orthoimagery from file, a digital number from 0 to 255 also be assigned to each pixel in each display band in a three-band image represented by red, blue, and green (RGB). Areas where the rectification process is incomplete because of incomplete data (that is, lack of elevation data, gaps) are represented with the numeric value of 0 or 128.</eaover>
<eadetcit>U.S. Department of the Interior, U.S. Geological Survey, 1996, Standards for Digital Orthophotos: Reston, VA.</eadetcit>
</overview>
</eainfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20041025</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USGS</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
<address>EROS Data Center</address>
<city>Sioux Falls</city>
<state>SD</state>
<postal>57198-0001</postal>
<country>US</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>1-605-594-6151</cntvoice>
<cnttdd>1-605-594-6933</cnttdd>
<cntfax>1-605-594-6589</cntfax>
<cntemail>custserv@usgs.gov</cntemail>
<hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM (Central Time)</hours>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
</metainfo>
</metadata>

